This matter, listen to Xie Xuan
この件は謝玄に任せよう
If Shilang's army really wants to retreat
もし石狼の大軍が本当に撤退するなら
Why go to such lengths
なぜわざわざ手間をかけて
To block information
情報を封鎖し
Not even a carrier pigeon can enter
伝書鳩一羽も城に入れないようにする
Now we're cornered
今や我は進退窮まり
And completely blind
しかも情報が全くない
At this time
このような時
We're most likely to become gamblers
最も博徒になりやすい
The more so
こういう時こそ
The less we should move
動いてはならない
Hurry to repair the walls
城壁の修復を急げ
Yes
はっ
Xie Xuan
謝玄
General Liu
劉将軍
Continue adding internal defenses
引き続き城内の布陣を強化せよ
Yes
はっ
No movement in the city yet
城内はまだ動きがないか
Reporting, General
将軍に報告します
Not yet
まだございません
That coward Prince of Jin
この腰抜けの晋王は
Is as timid as a mouse
まるで鼠のように臆病で
Scared by the general
将軍に脅されて
Won't move a step
一歩も動けないでいます
General
将軍
Chanyu Ayidai these past days
アイデイ単于がこの両日
Has been sending messages asking
何度も使者を送って催促してきます
If we don't take Yiyang soon
もしこれ以上弋陽を落とせなければ
Hurry, hurry, hurry
催促するな
Hurry your mother
くそったれめ
Prince of Jin Sikong Yao
怒鳴り声
I'll remember this
晋王司空耀俺は覚えたぞ
Return to camp
帰営だ
Tell the other side
もう一方に
To prepare for me
準備させろ
Report
報告
No activity found in the south
城南異常なし
No activity found in the west
城西異常なし
Could they really have withdrawn?
まさか本当に撤退したのか
What's going on?
どうした
Report
急報
Urgent report
急報です
Urgent report from the west
城西より急報
The Wuzhao have broken in from the west
鄔奴人が西から城に攻め込んできました
Into the city
城に入った
How could they enter the city?
どうやって城に入れる
Don't panic yet
落ち着け
What's the situation in the west now?
今西側はどういう状況だ
I've been hearing
この数日
Sounds these past days
ずっと物音が聞こえていました
I've been
私は最近
Resting poorly lately
よく眠れず
Always hearing
いつも
Tapping sounds
ドドドという音を聞き
Always dreaming
いつも夢で
Of Wuzhao horses trampling me
鄔奴の大馬が私を踏みつける夢を見ます
I thought it was hallucinations
幻覚かと思っていましたが
Now I know
今わかりました
The Wuzhao dug tunnels
鄔奴人が地下道を掘って
Undermining the wall foundations
城壁の根を崩し
The Wuzhao elite
鄔奴人の精鋭が
Have already emerged from the tunnels
すでに地下道から出てきて
Taking the gates
門を奪って道を開いています
General Liu is holding with his men
劉将軍が人を率いて死守しています
Report
報告
The Wuzhao army from the north has turned back
北側の鄔奴大軍が引き返してきました
Preparing to attack the city
攻城の準備をしています
The north
北側
Many volunteers at the west gate
西城門には義軍が多く
If they defect
もし裏切られたら
I'm afraid we can't hold
守りきれません
Yes, we can't hold
そうだ守りきれない
This is fighting on two fronts
両側から攻められて
But we have so few men
こんな少人数でどうする
Right
そうだ
How can we defend?
どうやって守る
We simply can't hold
全く守りきれない
Don't panic
慌てるな
Everyone
全員
Reinforce the north
北側を増援せよ
The northern front
北側前線は
Will be commanded by General Zhu
朱将軍の指揮に従え
Bring all available equipment
使える装備や器械は全て持って行け
Must stop the Wuzhao main force
必ず鄔奴の主力を食い止めろ
I accept the order
承知しました
You all
お前たち
Follow me
全員ついて来い
Yes
はっ
Xie Xuan
謝玄
Your general is here
はい